baker.edu 2017-03-18

# Academic Honor Code & College Policies | Baker College

#### Privacy Statement

This privacy statement applies to this Web site and certain other linked Web sites on servers owned and operated by Baker College. The privacy statement discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for all Baker College Web sites.

#### IP Address and Authentication

We log all connections to our Web servers. Those log files include your IP address. An IP address is NOT personally identifiable information, but general information about your location, your connection to the Internet, and the Internet Service Provider that is being used. We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our servers and to administer the Web sites.

However, when you connect to any of our systems through the use of individual or pooled modems, wireless connections on our campuses, or residence halls’ connections we ask you to authenticate using a user identification and password. We ask this so that these resources are used only by authorized students, staff, and faculty of this institution. In this case, the log files DO provide personally identifiable information. This information includes a history of the Web sites and pages that you visit.

Finally, for many of our specialized services, such as our e-mail systems, Blackboard, or the SOLAR System, your authentication allows us to provide you with specific information about your classes, grades, and financial status. These activities are also logged by us and include a history of the Web sites and pages that you visit.

In summary, on our sites we normally track only non-personal information but when you enter a user ID and password we log what you are doing while using our services. (This is one of the reasons you should never give anyone your user ID and password.)

#### Cookies

“Cookies” are small pieces of information stored in a user’s browser that give the user a unique identification. If you are attempting to access our restricted content, we will use cookies for authentication purposes only. All cookies are established on a per session basis, and are not stored permanently on your computer.

#### Personal Information

Baker College may collect personal information through various forms, surveys, or applications to allow us to contact you, improve our services, or create, complete, or update information about your records with Baker College. Information obtained via contact forms is only used for the defined purpose of contact. The user may be contacted through telephone, mail, or e-mail in response to the request being made.

Any personal information collected that pertains to financial aid is shared with specific third party loan agencies for the sole purpose of servicing student loans for Baker College

By using our Web sites, you represent that you are not less than 13 years of age. Personal information that is collected is treated as though it was submitted by an adult.

We do not sell or rent your contact information to third parties. However, we do provide this when we are required to disclose such information by law or in response to a request from a law enforcement agency or authority.  
Baker College is not responsible for personal information that is disclosed by users posting to discussion boards in Blackboard. All users of Blackboard are to exercise caution when disclosing personal information. Any information disclosed should be for educational purposes only.

Except with regard to any contact information you may provide us via the Web sites, all comments, feedback, information, or materials submitted to Baker College or in association with our Web sites will be considered non-confidential and the property of Baker College.

#### Security

Baker College Web sites have security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. Baker College does not guarantee the performance or adequacy of such security measures.

#### Links to Other Web Sites

The Web sites contain links to other Web sites that are not owned or operated by Baker College. The College is not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of third parties or the content or security of such Web sites.

#### Dissemination of Information

Baker College staff uses both personally identifiable information and non-personally identifiable information to aid them in diagnosing network and server issues and in planning for capacity and performance issues. Personally identifiable information is also used in diagnosing and attempting to solve problems of particular users at their request.

Baker College staff also uses personally identifiable information to aid in any investigation of unauthorized, inappropriate, illegal, or irresponsible use of computing resources. This information may be used internally to disable or remove accounts. Baker College will also cooperate with external agencies when required to disclose such information by law or in response to a request from a law enforcement agency or authority.

Baker College will not sell, rent, or otherwise disseminate information that it collects on its Web sites to other parties except as required by law and for financial aid purposes.

Baker College may make changes to this privacy statement. Any changes will be posted to this statement so that users are always aware items concerning their privacy.
